<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ndiff xmlns="http://diff.cs.unibo.it/jndiff" collapse="true" commentnode="true" emptynode="true" ltrim="true" rtrim="true"><delete xmlns="" nodecount="27" nodenumberA="170"><sec id="sec3dot1-remotesensing-10-00641"><title>3.1. Vegetation Monitoring and Precision Agriculture</title><p>Precision agriculture [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B63-remotesensing-10-00641"|-63-|/xref|-] has been the most common environmental monitoring application of UAS. High-spatial-resolution UAS imagery enables much earlier and more cost-effective detection, diagnosis, and corrective action of agricultural management problems compared to low-resolution satellite imagery. Therefore, UAS may provide the required information to address the needs of farmers or other users at the field scale, enabling them to make better management decisions with minimal costs and environmental impact [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B64-remotesensing-10-00641"|-64-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B65-remotesensing-10-00641"|-65-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B66-remotesensing-10-00641"|-66-|/xref|-].</p><p>Vegetation state can be evaluated and quantified through different vegetation indices from images acquired in the visible, red edge, and near-infrared spectral bands. Depending on their formulation, these can display a strong correlation with soil coverage and Leaf and Green Area Index (LAI and GAI), Crop Nitrogen Uptake (QN), chlorophyll content, water stress detection, canopy structure, photosynthesis, yield, and/or growing conditions [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B67-remotesensing-10-00641"|-67-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B68-remotesensing-10-00641"|-68-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B69-remotesensing-10-00641"|-69-|/xref|-]. As such, these vegetation indices may be exploited to monitor biophysical parameters.</p><p>Among the many available vegetation indices, the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI) is one that is most widely used [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B70-remotesensing-10-00641"|-70-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B71-remotesensing-10-00641"|-71-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B72-remotesensing-10-00641"|-72-|/xref|-]. UAS-NDVI maps can be at least comparable to those obtained from satellite visible observations and become highly relevant for a timely assessment of crop health status, with capacity to provide immediate feedback to the farmer. NDVI surveys performed with UAS, aircraft, and satellite demonstrate that low-resolution images generally fail in representing intrafield variability and patterns in fields characterized by small vegetation gradients and high vegetation patchiness [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7-remotesensing-10-00641"|-7-|/xref|-]. Moreover, UAS-derived NDVIs have shown better agreement with ground-based NDVI observations compared to satellite-derived NDVIs in several crop and natural vegetation types [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73-remotesensing-10-00641"|-73-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B74-remotesensing-10-00641"|-74-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B75-remotesensing-10-00641"|-75-|/xref|-]. As an example of the achievable resolution that can be obtained from UAVs, relative to some available high-resolution commercial satellite sensors, -|xref ref-type="fig" rid="remotesensing-10-00641-f003"|-Figure 3-|/xref|- shows a multi-sensor sequence of imagery collected over a date palm plantation in Saudi Arabia. The observed differences between vegetation patterns and resolvable resolution observed by UAS (compared to available satellite platforms) are clearly identified. The relative advantages of UAS in providing a level of detail that is comparable to field observations (or in deriving NDVI or other related vegetation indices for more in depth assessment) is illustrated by its capability of capturing both within and between canopy behavior.</p><p>In the last decade, particular attention has been given to the monitoring of vineyards because of their high economic value. Johnson et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B76-remotesensing-10-00641"|-76-|/xref|-] proposed one of the first applications where different sensors were used for determining measures related to chlorophyll function and photosynthetic activity, LAI, and plant health status (among other variables) to mapping vigor differences within fields. More recently, Zarco-Tejada et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B52-remotesensing-10-00641"|-52-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B77-remotesensing-10-00641"|-77-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78-remotesensing-10-00641"|-78-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B79-remotesensing-10-00641"|-79-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B80-remotesensing-10-00641"|-80-|/xref|-] demonstrated the potential for monitoring specific variables such as crop water stress index, photosynthetic activity, and carotenoid content in vineyards using multispectral, hyperspectral, and thermal cameras.</p><p>Based upon author experiences, farmers have expressed particular interest in monitoring crop conditions for the quantification of water demand, nitrogen status, or infestation treatments. Several of the variables or indices described above may be used for rapid detection of crop pest outbreaks or for mapping the status of crops. Likewise, monitoring soil water content is critical for determining efficient irrigation scheduling. The topsoil moisture content can be derived using RGB, NIR, and thermal bands [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B81-remotesensing-10-00641"|-81-|/xref|-]. The effective amount of water stored in the subsurface can be obtained by exploiting mathematical relationships between surface measurements and the root zone soil moisture, such as the Soil Moisture Analytical Relationship (SMAR) [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B82-remotesensing-10-00641"|-82-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B83-remotesensing-10-00641"|-83-|/xref|-].</p><p>As a further example, Sullivan et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B84-remotesensing-10-00641"|-84-|/xref|-] observed that the thermal infrared (TIR) emittance was highly sensitive to canopy state and can be used for monitoring soil water content, stomatal conductance, and canopy cover. TIR has similarly been used for the monitoring and estimation of soil surface characteristics such as microrelief and rill morphology [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85-remotesensing-10-00641"|-85-|/xref|-], soil water repellency [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B86-remotesensing-10-00641"|-86-|/xref|-], soil surface macropores [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B87-remotesensing-10-00641"|-87-|/xref|-], skin surface soil permeability [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B88-remotesensing-10-00641"|-88-|/xref|-], and overland and rill flow velocities by using thermal tracers [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B89-remotesensing-10-00641"|-89-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B90-remotesensing-10-00641"|-90-|/xref|-].</p><p>More specifically, the TIR emittance displays a negative correlation with stomatal conductance and canopy closure, indicating increasing canopy stress as stomatal conductance and canopy closure decreased. The crop water stress index (CWSI) [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B91-remotesensing-10-00641"|-91-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B92-remotesensing-10-00641"|-92-|/xref|-] calculated from leaf water potential can be used to determine the required frequency, timing, and duration of watering. In this regard, the CWSI, derived with a UAS equipped with a thermal camera, is frequently adopted to quantify the physiological status of plants, and, more specifically, leaf water potential in experimental vineyards or orchards [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B52-remotesensing-10-00641"|-52-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B80-remotesensing-10-00641"|-80-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B93-remotesensing-10-00641"|-93-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B94-remotesensing-10-00641"|-94-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B95-remotesensing-10-00641"|-95-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B96-remotesensing-10-00641"|-96-|/xref|-]. The derived CWSI maps can serve as important inputs for precision irrigation. Time series of thermal images can also be used to determine the variation in water status [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B97-remotesensing-10-00641"|-97-|/xref|-].</p><p>Using VIS–NIR (400–1000 nm) hyperspectral and multispectral analyses of simulated data has shown that soil attributes can be extracted from these spectral regions, particularly those most commonly used by the current UAS platforms [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B98-remotesensing-10-00641"|-98-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B99-remotesensing-10-00641"|-99-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B100-remotesensing-10-00641"|-100-|/xref|-]. These studies demonstrated that the VIS-NIR spectral region alone can open up new frontiers in soil mapping (as well as soil moisture content retrieval) using on-board multi- and hyperspectral UAS sensors without using heavyweight sensors operating in the SWIR (1–2.5 μm) region. Aldana-Jague et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B32-remotesensing-10-00641"|-32-|/xref|-] mapped soil surface organic carbon content (&lt;0.5 cm) at 12 cm resolution exploiting six bands between 450 and 1050 nm acquired by low-altitude multispectral imagers. D’Oleire-Oltmanns et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30-remotesensing-10-00641"|-30-|/xref|-] showed the applicability of UAS for measuring, mapping, and monitoring soil erosion at 5 cm resolution with an accuracy between 0.90 and 2.7 cm in the horizontal and 0.70 cm in the vertical directions. Detailed information about soil erosion can enhance proper soil management at the plot scale [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B31-remotesensing-10-00641"|-31-|/xref|-].</p><p>Such tools were further explored by Zhu et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B22-remotesensing-10-00641"|-22-|/xref|-], who investigated the ability to quantify the differences in soil nitrogen application rates using digital images taken from a UAS compared with ground-based hyperspectral reflectance and chlorophyll content data. They suggested that aerial photography from a UAS has the potential to provide input in support of crop decision-making processes, minimizing field sampling efforts, saving both time and money, and enabling accurate assessment of different nitrogen application rates. Therefore, such information may serve as input to other agricultural systems, such as tractors or specific UAS, that optimize fertilizer management.</p><p>UAS can also improve agronomical practices. Costa et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B101-remotesensing-10-00641"|-101-|/xref|-] described an architecture that can be employed to implement a control loop for agricultural applications where UAS are responsible for spraying chemicals on crops. Application of chemicals is controlled by the feedback obtained from a wireless sensor network (WSN) deployed on the crop field. They evaluated an algorithm to adjust the UAS route under changes in wind (intensity and direction) to minimize the waste of pesticides. Peña et al. [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B102-remotesensing-10-00641"|-102-|/xref|-,-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B103-remotesensing-10-00641"|-103-|/xref|-] explored the optimization of herbicide applications in weed–crop systems using a series of UAS multispectral images. The authors computed multiple data, which permitted both calculation of herbicide requirements and estimation of the overall cost of weed management operations in advance. They showed that the ability to discriminate weeds was significantly affected by the imagery spectra (type of camera) used as well as the spatial (flight altitude) and temporal (the date of the study) resolutions.</p><p>Among these technical advantages and constraints, the importance of the limitation of operational rules in using UAS in several countries needs to be highlighted. As an example, Jeunnette and Hart [-|xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B24-remotesensing-10-00641"|-24-|/xref|-] developed a parametric numerical model to compare aerial platform options (UAS vs airborne) to support agriculture in developing countries characterized by highly fragmented fields, but manned systems are still more competitive from an operational and cost/efficiency point of view because of the present limitations in altitude, distance, and speed of UAS. In particular, UAS become cost-competitive when they are allowed to fly higher than 300 m AGL (above ground level), while current limits are set around 120–150 m. This is a critical limitation for the use of UAS along with the fact that flights should be within visible line of sight (VLOS) in many jurisdictions.</p><p>All the applications described highlight the potential use of UAS in developing advanced tools for precision agriculture applications and for vegetation monitoring in general. With time, both technological advances and legislation will evolve and likely converge, further advancing the efficient use of such technologies.</p></sec></delete></ndiff>