<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><article article-type="review-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="en" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">remotesensing</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Remote Sensing</journal-title><abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="publisher">Remote Sens.</abbrev-journal-title><abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Remote Sensing</abbrev-journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2072-4292</issn><publisher><publisher-name>MDPI</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">remotesensing-10-006415</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject><p>Review</p><p>Additional Review data</p><p>other</p></subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title><p>On the Use of Unmanned Aerial Systems for Environmental Monitoring</p></article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id authenticated="true" contrib-id-type="orcid">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0225-144X</contrib-id><name><surname>Manfreda Oscaro</surname><given-names>Salvatore</given-names></name>-|xref rid="af1-remotesensing-10-00641" ref-type="aff"|-1-|/xref|- -|xref rid="c1-remotesensing-10-00641" ref-type="corresp"|-*-|/xref|-</contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id authenticated="true" contrib-id-type="orcid">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1279-5272</contrib-id><name><surname>McCabe</surname><given-names>Matthew F.</given-names></name>-|xref rid="af2-remotesensing-10-00641" ref-type="aff"|-2-|/xref|-</contrib></contrib-group><aff id="af1-remotesensing-10-00641"><label>1</label>Dipartimento delle Culture Europee e del Mediterraneo: Architettura, Ambiente, Patrimoni Culturali (DiCEM), Universita degli Studi della Basilicata, 75100 Matera, Italy</aff><aff id="af2-remotesensing-10-00641"><label>2</label>Water Desalination and Reuse Center, King Abdullah University of Science and Technology, 23955 Thuwal, Saudi Arabia</aff><author-notes><corresp id="c1-remotesensing-10-00641"><label>*</label>Correspondence:<email>salvatore.Manfreda@unibas.it</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>20</day><month>04</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>04</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>10</volume><issue>4</issue><elocation-id>641</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>12</day><month>03</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>17</day><month>04</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><p>permission 1</p><p>permission additional</p><copyright-statement>© 2018 by the authors.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2018</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access"><license-p>Licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland. This article is an open access article distributed under the terms and conditions of the Creative Commons Attribution (CC BY) license (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p>Environmental _|b|_monitoring_|/b|_ plays a central role in diagnosing climate and management hello impacts on natural and agricultural systems; enhancing the understanding of hydrological processes; optimizing the allocation and distribution of water resources; and assessing, forecasting, and even preventing natural disasters. Nowadays, most monitoring and data collection systems are based upon a combination of ground-based measurements, manned airborne sensors, and satellite observations. These data are utilized in describing both small- and large-scale processes, but have spatiotemporal constraints inherent to each respective collection system. Bridging the unique spatial and temporal divides that limit current monitoring platforms is key to improving our understanding of environmental systems. In this context, Unmanned Aerial Systems (UAS) have considerable potential to radically improve environmental monitoring. UAS-mounted sensors offer an extraordinary opportunity to bridge the existing gap between field observations and traditional air- and space-borne remote sensing, by providing high spatial detail over relatively large areas in a cost-effective way and an entirely new capacity for enhanced temporal retrieval. As well as showcasing recent advances in the field, there is also a need to identify and understand the potential limitations of UAS technology. For these platforms to reach their monitoring potential, a wide spectrum of unresolved issues and application-specific challenges require focused community attention. Indeed, to leverage the full potential of UAS-based approaches, sensing technologies, measurement protocols, postprocessing techniques, retrieval _|i|_algorithms_|/i|_, and evaluation techniques need to be harmonized. The aim of this paper is to provide an overview of the existing research and applications of UAS in natural and agricultural ecosystem monitoring in order to identify future directions, applications, developments, and challenges.</p><p>this is additional string that check style changes, this is additional string italic</p><p>this is item move text in one node text for move end</p><p>delete one node _|b|_alo_|/b|_</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>UAS</kwd><kwd>remote sensing</kwd><kwd>environmental monitoring</kwd><kwd>precision agriculture</kwd><kwd>vegetation indices</kwd><kwd>soil moisture</kwd><kwd>river monitoring</kwd></kwd-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1-remotesensing-10-00641" sec-type="intro"><title>1. Introduction</title><p>While UAS systems cannot compete with satellite imagery in terms of spatial coverage, they provide unprecedented spatial and temporal resolutions unmatched by satellite alternatives. Furthermore, they do so at a fraction of the satellite acquisition cost if the area of interest has relatively small extent. For example, a newly tasked high-resolution natural color image (50 cm/pixel) from a satellite (e.g., GeoEye-1) can cost up to 3000 USD. On the other hand, the initial outlay to acquire a single UAS with a natural color camera can be less than 1000 USD (see -|xref ref-type="app" rid="app1-remotesensing-10-00641"|-Appendix A-|/xref|-), with this delivering a dataset of high spatial resolution (several cm/pixel). Of course, the additional benefit of the UAS platform is that the temporal resolution is limited only by the number of flights (and power supply/battery capacity), so any cost equivalence is quickly overcome due to repeatability. The costs for acquiring UAS imagery are usually derived from the initial investment, the processing software, data storage, and associated (and ongoing) fieldwork expenses. However, after the initial investment, datasets can be delivered more often and at a higher resolution than by any other EO system.</p><p>but you didn't have to cut me off, make out like it never happened that we were nothing</p></sec></body></article>